我叫Oliver Queen
My name is Oliver Queen.
经历岛上地狱般的五年后
After five years on a hellish island,
我回来了 心怀一个目标...
I have come home with only one goal...
拯救这座城市
to save my city.
但为此我不能再像以前一样杀戮
But to do so, I can't be the killer I once was.
为了祭奠我的好友 我必须重塑自己
To honor my friend's memory, I must be someone else.
Thomas Merlyn之墓 1985-2013
我必须伪装自身
I must be something else.
"绿箭侠"前情提要...
Previously on "Arrow"...
被告人被判定无罪
The defendant is found not guilty.
你好 Moira
Hello, Moira.
Malcolm 你到底想怎样?
What do you want, Malcolm?
Thea是我的女儿
Thea is my daughter.
这些人找一艘七十年前的潜艇干什么?
What do these guys want with a seven year old sub?
它运载的东西 能够拯救人类
What's on it, it'll save the human race.
能拯救他吗?
Will it save him?
长官 事情有进展
Sir, there's been a development.
Cyrus兄弟...
Brother Cyrus...
感觉如何?
How do you feel?
更加强壮了
Stronger.
-=圣城家园SCG字幕组 http://hd.cnscg.com/=-
仅供翻译交流使用, 禁止用于商业用途
协调: Tracy
时间轴: Pisces夜
翻译: 初见 水果哥 yjk8654 伊娃 西皮
校对: 潇妹纸
那是什么?
What was that?
绿箭侠 第二季 第八集
Queen夫人 欢迎回到公司
Mrs. Queen, welcome back to the company.
- 谢谢  - 你今天真美
- Thank you.  - You look fabulous.
真的 比以前更美了 你做了头发吗?
Really, better than ever. Did you do something to your hair?
是的 没有狱友和守卫的监视
Yes, I shampooed it without eight women
我痛快地洗了个头发
and a guard watching me.
我是不是不该笑? 有人告诉我
Is it ok to laugh? Because I was ordered
为了避免尴尬 不要和你提坐牢的...
not to say anything about you being in prison, just to avoid any awkward...
- 事情  - 这就很尴尬了
- exchanges.  - Like that one.
好吧
Right.
在财政赤字之前 我们应该研究一下这些数据
We need to drill down on these numbers before the earnings call.
Oliver 我不知道
Oliver. I didn't realize
你母亲今天会到访
your mother was stopping by for a visit today.
她不是来访问的 这也是她的公司
Well, it's not a visit. This is her company, too.
当然了
Of course.
你好吗 Moira?
How are you, Moira?
平安回来了 Isabel
Back, Isabel.
Queen先生 能借一步说话吗?
Mr. Queen, may I speak to you for a minute?
如果我们再把Queen实业
What sort of message does it send
交给你母亲领导
to the investment committee, to the city,
调查委员会和市民们会怎么想?
if we hand Queen consolidated right back to your mother?
- 她被无罪释放了  - 陪审团说她无罪
- She was acquitted.  - By a jury.
市民们可不这么想 Oliver
Not by the city. Oliver.
你不仅是一个儿子
Stop thinking like a son
更是这家公司的首席执行官
and start thinking like a CEO.
Oliver啊
Oliver.
有抢劫发生
There's been a break-in.
该死!
Damn!
这扇门是用超强钛合金制成的
This door is made of expanded reinforced titanium.
他们是怎么弄破的?
What did they use to do this?
还不清楚 没有爆炸的痕迹
Not sure yet. No sign of any explosives.
也许是用吊车 或是铲车
Maybe a crane, maybe a forklift.
我猜测他们至少有三个人 也可能是四个
I'm guessing there was at least three of them, maybe four.
而他们进出的时间说明...
And given how quick they got in and out of here...
他们手法很快
they were fast.
哇 嘿 等一下!
Whoa, hey, stop, wait!
怎么回事啊?
What's wrong there?
你知道他们为什么那么热衷于抢劫吗?
Any idea what these guys were so hot to break in here for?
你把一台空闲的地震仪放在这里
You didn't happen to leave a spare earthquake machine
肯定有目的吧?
lying around, did you?
不好意思
Sorry.
这是监控录像里的片段
This is what we're able to pull off the security cameras.
我们只拍到了他自己
He was the only guy we got on video.
他的同伙应该随后才到
The rest of the crew must have come in after him.
其实 只有一个人
Actually, it was only one guy.
不好意思 我来晚了
Ah, sorry I'm late.
因为第二辆火车晚点了
But actually, my train was late. Well, the second one.
第一辆我没赶上 都怪那个出租车司机
The first one I did miss, but that was my cab driver's fault.
我查了电子地图...
I've got this great traffic app, and...
但是司机坚持说他才是对的
but he thought that he was right.
不过谢天谢地 我来了
I'm here now, though. So.
好极了 你是谁啊?
Great. Who the hell are you?
你父母知道你来这里吗?
And do your parents know that you're here?
我是Barry Allen
I'm Barry Allen.
来自警察厅总部
I'm from the central city police department.
我是犯罪现场调查科的
I'm with the crime scene investigation unit.
我们在查一个案子
We're working on a case with some similar
中心城发现了一些类似的神秘元素
unexplained elements in central city,
所以当在系统里看到这里抢劫案的记录
so when the report of your robbery came over the wire,
我的上司就把我派来了
my captain sent me up here.
你以为这扇们就像锡纸一样
And you think one guy ripped through this door
一个人就能进去?
like it was tin foil?
一个很强壮的人就能进去
One very strong guy, yeah.
扭断一个人的脖子需要大约
Uh, it takes about 1,250 foot pounds of torque
1250尺磅的力量
to break someone's neck.
你们看到门卫脖子上的伤痕了吗?
You see the marks on the guard's neck?
上面的淤青表明 凶手仅用一只手就把他掐死了
The bruising pattern suggests the killer used only one hand.
我猜你肯定不知道
I'm guessing you don't know how hard it is
扭断一个人的脖子有多不容易
to break someone's neck.
嗯? 不 我不知道
Hmm? No. No idea.
我们需要一份物品清单
Uh, we're going to need a list of the entire inventory here
对照确认一下丢失的物品
to figure out exactly what was stolen.
事实上我知道什么丢了
Actually, I think I know what was stolen.
是一台离心机 工业用离心机
A centrifuge. An industrial centrifuge.
有可能是核心企业2BX 900型号的
Probably the Cord Enterprises 2BX 900.
也许是第六代的
Maybe the six series.
都是三缸系统
Both have a three column base.
看这 有三个被弄坏的螺丝钉
Here, you can see the three sets of broken bolts
小偷... 直接把他们拔了下来
Where the thief just... ripped it out of the ground.
离心机是干什么用的?
And what exactly is a centrifuge?
它能够分离液体
It separates liquids.
不同的向心力使密度大的液体
The centripetal acceleration causes denser substances
向转轴外部移动
to separate out along the radial direction.
这样密度小的液体就被分离出来了
And lighter objects move to the top.
你刚才说你叫什么来着?
What did you say your name was again?
我叫Barry 姓Allen
Barry. Allen.
我是Felicity 姓Smoak
Felicity. Smoak.
裂缝一直
Um, you can see the cracks
延伸到门口 还有脚印
heading towards the door. Footsteps.
只有一个人
One guy.
但这只是我的猜想
Anyway, it's just a theory.
很多证据都说明只有一个人
One backed by a lot of evidence.
肯定还有其他解释
There has to be another explanation.
嗯 你说得对
Yeah. I'm sure you're right.
你可以去通知一下咱们的朋友吗
You might want to fill our mutual friend in on this.
嗯 别担心
Yeah. Don'worry.
我想他已经开始调查了
I'm sure he's already on it.
我们得换个方向
We need to change directions
- 往南10度  - 我们得休息一下
- 10 degrees north.  - We need to rest.
如有Ivo和他的手下没有死光
If Ivo and any of his men survived that blast,
他们肯定在找我们
they'll be tracking us.
我们得接着走
We keep moving.
就停五分钟
Five minutes.
你来照顾一下他
You watch him, please.
好的
Of course.
你相信他们吗?
Do you believe them?
这个回转石能让我们找到那艘破潜艇?
That this hosen will lead us to a wrecked Japanese sub?
这是Ivo的想法
Ivo seems to think so.
我只希望能在潜艇上
I just hope whatever miracle serum
找到那个万能血清
they're after is actually onboard.
他很需要
For his sake.
你了解那个女孩吗?
How do you know that girl?
在我爸的船上...
Sara was on my father's boat...
Sara和我在一起
with me.
那照片上的那个女孩呢?
What about the girl in the picture?
是叫Laurel吗?
Laurel?
你说你很爱的那个女孩
The girl you told me you were in love with.
Sara是她妹妹
Sara is her sister.
我想去走走
I feel like taking a walk.
谁想一起去?
Anyone care to join me?
看来这些年发生了不少事情
I guess a lot's happened in the last year.
Oliver啊
Oliver.
从应用科学部拿到了物品清单
Got the final inventory from Applied Sciences.
那个中央警局犯罪调查科的人说的没错
That CSI from central city was right.
只有一样东西被偷 离心机
The only thing missing is a centrifuge.
看看这个 我从应用科学部对街的
You have to see this. I pulled up CC traffic camera footage
监控录像里找到的
from across the street of Applied Sciences.
这是警报器响了三分钟的时候
This is three minutes after the alarm went off.
有什么能帮你的吗 警官?
Can we help you with something, detective?
哦 犯罪科的人算不上是警官
Oh, CSIs aren't actually detectives.
我们都不配枪
We don't even carry guns.
只有一些塑料设备
Just some plastic baggies.
哦 我的设备该放在哪里?
Uh, where should I set up my equipment?
- 我带你去  - 这是什么情况?
- I'll show you.  - What's going on?
你的助手说
Your assistant said that you preferred
你想要在室内进行调查
to keep the investigation in house,
所以我和副巡长清理了现场来帮忙
So I cleared it with my captain to give you a hand.
你在搞什么呢?
What are you doing?
我们要找出入侵者
We need to find this intruder.
而他看起来比我们对此案更了解
And he seems to know more about it than any of us.
鉴证科不是我的专长 所以...
Forensic science isn't exactly my forte, so...
我们需要他的帮助
I'd say we need him.
不是吗?
Wouldn't you?
好吧
Mm-hmm.
我带你转转
I'll show you around.
我怎么觉得你比Felicity的这位新朋友知道的更多呢?
Why am I getting the feeling you know more about this than Felicity's new friend?
希望我想错了
Pray I'm wrong.
嗨 今早在办公司发生的事
Hi. I'm sorry about what happened
我很抱歉
at the office this morning.
很多人都认为我是侥幸逃过谋杀罪的处罚 Oliver
There are a lot of people who think I got away with murder, Oliver.
可能是吧
Maybe I did.
妈妈 无论是审判 还是所谓的阴谋"大事业"
Mom, the trial, the Undertaking,
还有Malcolm merlyn之类的 这些事情都过去了
Malcolm merlyn, all of that is behind us now.
我们要让别人明白这些
And we need everyone to see that.
- 我们能做什么呢?  - 举办宴会
- How are we going to do that?  - We throw a party.
嗨 Thea
Thea.
嗨 Roy
Roy.
我好像听到你们在谈论举办宴会的事情 是吧?
Did I hear you guys say something about a party?
为妈妈举办的宴会 欢迎她回到Queen企业
A welcome back to Queen consolidated party for mom.
我不想举办宴会
I don't think so.
要想让一切回归正轨
If things are going to get back to normal,
那我们就得先回归正常的生活
then we need to start acting normal.
正常的生活就需要举办一场盛宴
Normal for us is a lavish party.
哦 抱歉 Queen夫人 我不能留下来吃早午饭了
Oh. I'm sorry, Mrs. Queen, I can't stay for brunch.
我们要出去一下
I guess we got to go.
回见
Bye.
一切交给我来搞定
I'll take care of everything.
你到底在找什么?
What exactly are you looking for?
入侵者的鞋底接触过地面
Your thief's shoes touched the ground,
这就意味着 他会留下蛛丝马迹
which means he tracked in dozens of clues
让我们能查出最近几天他去过的地方
as to where he's been the past few days.
找到了
Got ya.
马上就好
Shouldn't take long.
你见过他 是吧?
So you've seen him, right?
治安维持者?
The vigilante?
据说他救过你
I read that he saved you.
他长什么样?
What was he like?
一袭绿色装备
Green.
绿色
很有趣 不是吗?
That's interesting, right?
我是指 他为什么选择绿色呢?
I mean, why green?
黑色能够更好的掩饰身份
Black would be better for stealth,
而迷彩色呢
and urban camouflage.
我个人认为
Me, personally,
他可能是在森林
I think that he trained in some sort of like forest
或者丛林里训练过
or jungle environment,
绿色就是这个象征
and the green is a nod to that.
我没仔细想过关于治安维持者的事情
I don't give the vigilante much thought.
警察调查显示他用碳钢的箭
Police reports show that he uses carbon arrows,
要是他换成铝碳合金的箭
but if he switched to an aluminum carbon composite,
他的射程能更远
he would have far better penetration.
也许他觉得这样的射程足够了
Maybe he thinks he penetrates just fine.
还想知道更多吗?
Do you want to know something else?
我觉得他有搭档
I think that he has partners.
他的搭档一定很精通计算机技术
Definitely someone with a background in computer sciences.
可能吧
Yeah.
为什么你对治安维持者这么感兴趣?
Why are you so interested in the vigilante?
在我十一岁的时候 妈妈被人谋杀
When I was 11, my mom was murdered.
抱歉
I'm so sorry.
凶手却一直逍遥法外
They never caught the guy who did it.
也许他能将凶手绳之以法
Maybe he would have.
土壤成分... 含有晶状结构
The soil... there's a crystalline structure in it.
真奇怪
That's weird.
哪里不对了?
What's weird?
是糖
It's sugar.
Sin 你说有紧急状况
Sin, you said this was an emergency.
无意冒犯 不过Thea不该来这里
No offense, but Thea, you shouldn't be here.
我为什么不能来我家俱乐部的小巷?
In the alleyway of the club I own?
是关于我朋友Max的事
It's my friend Max.
他失踪了 我们足足一周都没见过他
He's missing. I haven't seen him for a week, no one has.
他一定出了什么事
Something happened to him.
我猜你也许认识能帮上忙的人
I figured you knew someone who could help.
Roy会帮忙的
Roy can help you.
我还以为你不希望我参与这些事呢
I thought you wanted me to stay out of trouble.
我还挺喜欢你路见不平拔刀相助的个性
I kind of like that you never turn away from someone who needs help.
我找人照看一下俱乐部
I'll just get someone to cover the club.
你什么意思?
What do you mean?
哦 我要和你一起行动
Oh, I'm coming with you.
听说你要举办宴会
I hear you're throwing a party.
可是我没收到邀请
I didn't get my invite.
我要到哪里去邀请你呢?
Where exactly should I have addressed it?
Starling市公墓吗?
Starling city cemetery?
我知道 你巴不得我在墓地里腐烂呢
I know that's where you wish I was right now.
我对自己的儿子说谎
Lying beside my son.
难道还要我为你感到难过吗 Malcolm?
Am I supposed to feel sorry for you, Malcolm?
是你害死了Tommy
You killed Tommy.
你害死了自己的儿子
You killed your son.
- 你不能抢走我的女儿  - 是我们的女儿
- You cannot have my daughter.  - Our daughter.
我觉得那一晚我们都很需要人陪
I think we both needed someone that night.
我为做了对不起Rebecca的事情内疚
I felt so bad about betraying Rebecca's memory
于是离开了Starling市
that I left Starling.
离开了Tommy
Left Tommy behind.
我就是那时候去的南峰
That's when I made my way to Nanda Parbat,
在那里我找到了人生新目标
where I found my new purpose.
不得不说 Moira
In a way, Moira,
是你造就了如今的我
You made me the man I am today.
Thea是无辜的
Thea is innocent.
她很爱Robert
She loved Robert.
请你不要把她牵扯进来
Please don't take that away from her,
求求你了
I'm begging you.
Thea是我唯一的牵挂了
Thea is all I have left.
告诉她真相
Tell her the truth,
马上就告诉她
and tell her soon.
有进展吗?
You found something?
我们有新发现
We found something.
在入侵者的鞋印里
There were trace amounts of sucrose
我们发现了一些蔗糖和特殊的污泥成分
and a spec of dirt the killer dragged in here on his boot.
我突然想到  一公里之外有个炼糖厂
Which got me thinking. There is a sugar refinery
在它附近的岛上
two miles from here. The land around it
到处都有废糖料 于是我开始顺藤摸瓜
is suffused in waste sugar. So I checked.
发现几天前 他们有台运输车被盗走了
They had a delivery truck stolen a few days ago.
他们被盗卡车的规格型号
Their truck matches the make and model
与入侵者偷走离心机时用的卡车是一样的
of the truck the thief used to steal the centrifuge.
- 能追踪到那辆车吗?  - 正在追踪
- Can you track the vehicle?  - We've been trying.
那是什么?
What was that?
你一定会震惊的
You're not going to believe this.
那辆被盗的卡车 刚才被用来抢劫血库了
The truck, it was just used to rob a blood bank.
- 你确定吗?  - 确定
- Are you sure?  - Yeah. Our guy
那家伙刚刚抢劫了三万毫升的阴性O型血
just made off with 30,000 ccs of o-negative.
什么 难道他不仅力大无穷 而且还吸血?
What, he has super strength, likes blood?
别告诉我是吸血鬼现身了
Please don't tell me we suddenly believe in vampires.
我们应该把这个情况报告给警局
We should give this information to the local police.
我... 我去报警
I'll... take care of that.
你在中心城也处理过类似的案件吗?
Did you say that you were working a similar case in central city?
差不多
Oh, yeah, um...
是类似的案件
Yeah, you know, it's similar.
线索类似
Has similar elements.
有很多共同点
A lot of similarities.
好吧
Right. Yeah.
帮我查查这个孩子的背景?
I want you to look into this allen kid.
他隐瞒了不少事
There's more to him than he's letting on.
我觉得他图谋不轨
His intentions seem pretty clear to me.
那就交给你了
Just do it, please.
Oliver 你打算什么时候
Oliver, when are you going to tell me
告诉我事情的内幕?
what exactly we're up against?
哎唷!
Yeooww!
抱歉
Sorry.
啊
Ahh.
谢谢
Thank you.
你猜对了 我是了解一些内幕
You were right to ask if I knew more than I was letting on.
以前 我见过像他这样力大无的人
I've seen men with abilities like that before.
你见过?
You have?
在哪?
Where?
岛上
The island.
我在那逃亡的第二年 我们...
My second year marooned there, we...
我无意中发现了一个
I came across the remains
二战时的日本军事设施
of a japanese world war II military project.
这是一个旨在制造人体武器的血清
It was a serum designed to create human weapons.
人体武器 我去 然后就是外星人了?
Human weapons. My god, what's next, aliens?
这是真的 Diggle
This is real, Diggle.
我在岛上的那五年
Those five years that I was away,
遇见了很多...
I came across things that just...
无法解释的事
defy explanation.
当时有个医生叫Ivo
There's a doctor, his name is Ivo,
他到岛上来
and he came to the island
在人身上测试血清
to test the serum on people.
那些活下来的人 他们的忍耐力
The ones that survived, their endurance,
反应和力量都有所提高
reflexes and strength were all enhanced.
你觉得Ivo在starling市?
And you think this Ivo's in starling city?
他已经死了
He's dead.
所有他注射过血清的人都死了
And so is everyone that he injected with the serum.
最后一个... 是我烧死的
The last of which... I burned.
你觉得有人找到了配方
You think someone found the recipe.
那离心机和大量的血液
The centrifuge and a large supply of blood.
我觉得有人想造出更多的血清
I think someone wants to make more of it.
非常多
A lot more.
你咋不接着在阿鲁巴岛上逃亡
Why couldn't you have been marooned on Aruba?
还有第三种组成... 强效镇定剂
There's a third component... a strong sedative.
我还是喜欢你把这玩意
I think I preferred it
留在别人身体里
when you left these in people.
你去分析箭头上的血液
I need you to analyze the blood on the arrowhead.
如果我们找到他们用的是哪种镇定剂
If we can figure out which sedative they're using...
我们就能找到下次劫案会在哪
We can figure out where the next robbery will be.
我和Barry会立即着手
Barry and I will get right on it.
看来她已经被迷住了
I think our Miss Smoak is smitten.
Diggle 你查到Allen的底细了吗?
Diggle, what did you find out about Mr. Allen?
他说了谎
He's not who he says he is.
你还好吧?
How are you holding up?
我想要个更好看的拐杖
I could do with a better looking crutch.
看起来你俩很亲密啊
You two seem like you've gotten pretty chummy.
我们到了
We're here.
水线之下一定有个裂缝
There must be a fissure in the island
才能让它进来那么深
below the waterline for it to come that far inland.
不可思议
Unbelievable.
他们把硝酸放在氨旁边?
They have nitric acid next to hydrazine?
高锰酸放在丙酮上边?
Permanganates on top of acetone?
危险这个词就是这么来的啊
This is the definition of dangerous.
既然这么危险 就别动它们了
If it's so dangerous, maybe you shouldn't be touching them.
Barry啊
Barry.
我从警察局那里拿到
I managed to get a sample
凶手的血样
of the perpetrator's blood from the police department.
我们需要把血液里的血清分离出来
We need to isolate a sedative in the blood.
也许这样能找到那些小偷
It could lead us to the thief.
警察怎么搞到的?
How did the police get it?
很明显绿箭侠用箭射中了他
Apparently the vigilante shot him with an arrow.
真的假的
You're kidding.
你知道这意味着什么吗?
You know what this means, right?
说明绿箭侠在和我们同一个案子!
This means the vigilante's working the same case we are!
自己想象吧
Heh. Go figure.
你又是怎么弄来的?
How did you get it?
Oliver有很多关系
Oliver has a lot of connections.
好吧
Wow.
为一个亿万富翁工作可真方便
Pays to work for a billionaire.
其实我带回家的也没什么特别
Actually my take home's nothing special.
尤其是我很少在家
Especially given I am rarely at home,
每天晚上都和他在一起
since I'm with him every night.
啊 我没注意到你和他...
Ah. Well, I didn't realize you and he were...
不是
Oh, no.
是工作 他... 和我
Work. He... and I
不是 我不喜欢Oliver
are not, no, I do not like Oliver.
我收到了一个
Um, I was invited
工作站的邀请
to a work function.
是个派对
It's a party.
我能带一个伴一起去
And I have a plus-one.
我觉得带你去...
I was thinking you would make
会很好
a really good... plus-one.
不用跳舞吧?
There's not going to be dancing, is there?
我跳舞实在太丑了
I'm not just not too good on my feet.
哦
Ohh.
一股恶臭
It reeks in here.
我猜你的朋友不是很爱画风景
I guess your friend wasn't too into painting seascapes.
Max和别的饥饿艺术家没什么区别...
Max is like any starving artist...
饥饿
Starving.
我没地方去的时候 就来他这
But I could always crash here when I didn't have a place to stay.
这献血是一周以前的事了
Hey, this blood drive was a week ago.
你说他什么时候失踪的?
When did you say he went missing?
就是那天
That day.
我是Daily
It's Daily.
有人在找Mxwell Stanton
Someone's looking for Maxwell Stanton.
他们会找到他的
And they should find him.
明白 Blood兄弟
Yes, Brother Blood.
血液维持着生命
Blood provides life.
血液带来权力
Blood provides power.
有了权力...
And with power...
我就可以为所欲为
there's no limit to what I can do.
中心城还有一天就会创造历史
Central city is just a day away from making history
充满争议的S.T.A.R.实验室的粒子加速器
when the controversial S.T.A.R. Lab's particle accelerator
马上就要启动了
is finally turned on.
很棒吧?
Pretty cool, right?
你知道强子对撞机启动以后
You know there's been a hundred percent increase
地震的频率高了一倍吧
in earthquakes since they've turned on the large hadron collider.
- 这都是误解  - 是吗 说说
- That data is misleading.  - Oh, do tell.
你知道什么是误解 对吧?
You know about misleading, don't you?
你在说什么?
What are you talking about?
他不是CSI的人 他只是一个助手
He's not from CSI, he's an assistant.
你的上司还不知道你在Starling市
Whose bosses don't know you're in Starling.
中心城也没有类似的案件
And there is no similar case in central city.
说说吧 Barry...
So tell me, Barry...
你到底想干嘛?
What are you really doing here?
我告诉过你我妈被谋杀了
I told you my mom was murdered.
是你父亲干的
By your father.
他没有
He didn't do it.
你说警察没有找到凶手
You said that the police didn't find the man who killed her.
警察觉得是他干的
The police think they did.
我爸被判了终生监禁
My dad has been serving a life sentence.
他们不相信我
They didn't believe me.
不相信什么?
About what?
我当时11岁
I was 11.
有一天晚上...
One night...
有人闯入了我家 像一阵飓风
something just came into our house, like a tornado.
一团迷雾
A blur.
从那迷雾里 我看见一个人
Somewhere inside the blur, I saw a person.
我爸爸和他搏斗
My dad went to fight it.
我想靠近他们 但是突然...
I tried to get 'em when suddenly...
我就在20个街区之外了
I was 20 blocks away from our house.
没有人相信我
Nobody believed me.
他们觉得我是在庇护我爸爸
They thought I was trying to cover for my father.
但我那天晚上看见的
But what I saw that night
千真万确
was real.
和有人赤手空拳
As real as the man that ripped down
撕下那扇铁门一样千真万确
that metal door with his bare hands.
这就是为什么我想介入这样的案子
That's why I look into cases like this.
没有人相信的案子
The ones nobody believes are possible.
如果我能搞清楚这样的一个案子
Maybe if I can just make sense of one,
也许就能找到杀我妈妈的凶手
I might be able to find out who really killed my mother.
让我爸爸重获自由
And free my dad.
对不起我骗了你
I am sorry I lied to you.
再找一个伴吧
Better find another plus one.
他喜欢自己冒充的身份
He did like about who he really was.
我们每天都在干什么?
And what do we do everyday?
嘿
Hey.
这里进展如何?
How's everything going in there?
晚上好 Queen氏家族
Good evening, Queens.
- 能借一步说话吗?  - 好的
- Can I have a word?  - Yeah.
对不起啊 之前我反应过度了
I'm sorry if I overreacted a little bit earlier.
你也知道?
Oh, you think?
现在你得向你妈妈道歉 不是我
Look, right now, you need to apologize to your mother. Not me.
道什么歉?
For what?
因为你错了
Your being wrong.
想来只有在因为谋杀受审的时候
I guess these days, I only draw a crowd
我才能吸引点人吧
when I'm on trial for murder.
妈 你没必要...
Mom, you don't have to...
有客人来就好
We have guests.
不管来得多少
However few of them there are.
这不是你的错 Ollie
This is not your fault, Ollie.
你妈妈怎么样?
How's your mom doing?
我们Queen家族的女人... 没什么会难倒我们
Oh, you know us Queen women... Nothing gets to us.
你可真有你爸的范
You must take after your dad.
抱歉
Sorry.
Sin 什么事?
Sin. What's up?
- 我找到Max了  - 在哪儿?
- I found Max.  - Where?
- 我这就来  - 找到Max了?
- I'm on my way.  - They find Max?
呃 不
Um, no.
她只是想让我过去下
She just wants me to stop by.
我和你一起去
I can come with you.
你应该待在这 你妈妈需要你
You should stay here. Your Mom needs you.
好了 我迟点打给你
Ok, I'll call you later.
要跳舞吗?
Time for a dance?
不太想和你跳 Oliver
Not really feeling like dancing with you, Oliver.
我懂的
I know.
所以我叫他来了
And that is why I called him.
温馨提示...
FYI...
他会受到公开审问
They will card him at the bar.
- 嗨  - 嗨
- Hi.  - Hi.
说真的我不会跳舞
I was serious about not being able to dance.
但我会牵着你的手晃起来
But I'll hold your hands and sway.
- 同意  - 好的
- Sold.  - Ok.
我警告过你了
I tried to warn you.
我忽略你了
I tried to ignore you.
抱歉 Oliver
I am sorry, Oliver.
好吧
Yeah.
Oliver帮你办了个愉快的聚会
Oliver threw you a lovely party.
Oliver是个孝顺的儿子
Oliver's a good son,
虽然看人不是很准
if not the best judge of character.
一切还好吧?
Is everything ok?
一切都很完美
Everything's going perfectly.
他命不长了
He doesn't have long.
如果这种特效药在船上 我们必须马上找出来
If this miracle drug is onboard, then we need to find it now.
Slade 我们很快就回来 好吗?
Slade, be back in a few minutes, ok?
我会没事的
I'll just get comfortable.
这边
Come on.
在那
There.
特效药
Mirakuru.
Miracle.
我从不相信是真的
I was never sure it was real.
如果给Slade吃会怎样?
What happens if we give it to Slade?
他需要先打血液镇定剂
He needs a sedative in his bloodstream first.
他们可能有溴化钾或者巴比妥
They might have potassium bromide or barbital.
喔
Ohh.
是空的
It's empty.
如果不打镇静剂会怎样?
What happens if we give it to him without the sedative?
会怎样 Sarah!
Sarah!
他肯定会死掉
He'll die, for sure.
反正他迟早都会死
He's going to die anyway.
什么声音?
What was that?
Ivo和他的手下 他们在潜艇上
Ivo and his men. They're on the sub.
- 你联系了吗?  - 联系过了
- Have you made contact?  - Yes.
他说接受并感谢你的信息
He said to tell you that your information was gratefully accepted.
谢谢
Thank you.
那是谁?
Who was that?
不用担心
Nothing to worry about.
今晚谢谢你 Oliver 晚会很开心
Thank you for tonight, oliver. It was a lovely party.
对不起 我让你难堪了
I'm so sorry that I put you through that.
听着 我不在乎这座城市的其他人怎么看我
Oh, listen, I don't care what anyone else in this city thinks of me.
我只在乎你俩对我的看法
I only care what you two think.
我要回办公室了 失陪
And I have to get back to the office. Excuse me.
对了 Thea
Thea.
我有件事想告诉你
There's something I need to tell you.
好啊 什么事?
Sure. What is it?
我爱你
I love you.
我也爱你
I love you, too.
是的
Yes.
是的 长官 我...
Yes, sir. I...
是的 主管 我知道这不是第一次了
Yes, Director, I know that this is not the first time.
是的 长官 我真的很重视我的工作 非常重视
Yes, sir, I do value my job, very much.
我会搭下一班火车回去
Look, I will be on the next train.
嗯 我今晚就回去 好的
Mmhmm. I'll be back tonight. Ok.
谢...
Thank...
我上司知道我没有食物中毒
Well, my boss found out I don't have food poisoning.
如果想保住工作的话
I need to get back to central city
我要马上回中心城了
If I still want to be employed.
我不想失业
Which I do.
告诉Starling市警察局 小偷血中的镇静剂
Tell the SCPD that the sedative in the thief's blood
是克他命 是管制药物中的第三类
is ketamine. It's a schedule three controlled substance.
应该不难找到
It shouldn't be too hard to track.
好的 我会确认他们找得到
Yeah, I'll make sure they get it.
- 谢谢  - 和你共事...
- Thank you.  - It was really nice...
- 谢谢你做...  - 真好
- Thank you for...  - working with you.
没有你 任何事情...
Everything, we couldn't have done it...
都完成不了
without you.
再见 Felicity
Good bye, Felicity.
再见
Good bye.
Max啊!
Max!
- 放开 放手!  - Max! 放开我!
- Get off, let go!  - Max! Get off of me!
喂! 放开她
Hey! Let her go.
住手!
Cut it out!
笨蛋警察
Stupid cops.
他们说Max过量吸毒了
They're saying Max oded.
- 他有吸毒吗?  - 没有!
- Was he using?  - No!
他靠献血赚钱
He made extra cash donating blood.
如果他过量吸毒 你觉得医院
You really think the hospital would let him
会让他献血吗?
be a donor if he was an addict?
喂 别待在这 小子
Hey. Can't be here, kid.
走吧
Let's go.
他们发现小偷的血液中有微量克他命
They found trace amounts of ketamine in the thief's blood.
这是一种用盐酸盐做的普通外科麻醉剂
It's a common surgical anesthesia derived from hydrochloric salt.
你可以用这找到他吗?
Can you use that to track him?
根据目前血液取样中的浓度比例
With the current concentration ratio in the blood sample,
只有一个地方可能有足够浓度的镇静剂
there's only one possible location with a large enough quality of the sedative
与血液量一一对应
that correlates with the amount of blood
偷来的离心机可以处理
The stolen centrifuge can process.
那是什么? 没有标志
What is it? There's no sign.
阿格斯可不爱打广告
ARGUS doesn't like to advertise.
那是个避难所 在棕榈湖的边上
It's a disaster bunker. Right on the edge of the glades.
阿格斯在全国各地都设了这些仓库
ARGUS has them all over the country.
他们储备救援物资...
They store relief supplies...
食物 衣服... 药品
Food, clothing... medicine.
我这就去
I'm on my way.
Oliver啊...
Oliver...
我说的话连我自己都不信
I can't believe I'm actually saying this.
根据剪头的弯曲程度...
The way this arrowhead is bent...
意味着这个贼的肌肉密度
It means our thief's muscle density
至少达到了每立方英尺120磅的密度
is at least 120 pounds per cubic foot.
等同于普通混凝土的密度
That's almost the same density as common concrete.
你的箭也许能割伤他 但阻止不了他
Your arrows may cut this guy, but they will not stop him.
Felicity 我之前打败过这种人
Well, I've beat someone like this before, Felicity.
我可以再赢一次
I can do it again.
如果你不能呢?
What if you can't?
Oliver啊
Oliver.
现在这个针剂可以救你...
Now this, it could save you...
也有可能杀了你
or it could kill you.
看你的表情
By the looks on your faces,
横竖都是死
I'm going to die anyway.
抱歉
Sorry.
抱歉什么?
For what?
抱歉我说不出我有多难过
For not telling you how I really feel.
打吧
Do it.
不!
No!
什么?
What?
我需要你帮我
I need your help.
我朋友的一个朋友
A friend of mine's friend, well,
警察判断他吸毒过量致死 但我们觉得
the cops think he oded, but we think
- 是谋杀  - 怎么说?
Well, he wasn't an addict, for starters. And this...
首先他之前不是瘾君子 还有...
- He was murdered.  - Why?
这种死状和我见过的吸毒过量的死状不同
This doesn't look like any od I've ever seen.
你别管了
Stay away from that.
你知道什么?
You know something?
他到底发生了什么?
What happened to him?
是你让我在这个城市做你的眼线
You're the one who told me to be your eyes and ears on the streets.
你知道吗 这样还不够
You know what, that is not good enough for me anymore.
行 那咱们就掰了吧
Fine. Then we're done altogether.
我不跟你了!
I don't need you!
我朋友他们会帮我的
I have friends that can help me.
你阻止不了我们的
You can't stop us.
自找的
Slow you down.
我以为增加保安就没什么事了
And I thought it couldn't hurt to add extra security guards.
对他们有事
It hurt them.
真糟糕
Badly.
你把Thea保护起来了?
Have you prepared Thea?
没有
No.
你根本就靠近不了Thea 也没有机会跟她说话
You will not go near Thea, you will not speak to her
你再也踏进不了这栋房子了
and you will never set foot in this house again.
Moira 我放过你
I set you free, Moira.
你的命在我手里
Your life belongs to me.
我一直害怕你
I am through being afraid of you.
你觉得你能阻止我?
You think you can stop me?
那绿箭侠都杀不了我
Even the vigilante couldn't kill me.
是 他杀不了
No, he couldn't.
但我知道谁能
But I know someone who can.
雷霄古可以
Ra's Al Ghul.
你怎么知道这个名字?
How do you know that name?
我以前不知道
Well, I didn't.
不过你提到南峰我就知道了
Until you mentioned Nanda Parbat.
影武者联盟 不管他们的目标多变态
The league of assassins, however twisted their aims,
其成员都必然听从联盟的命令
believes very deeply in a code of honor.
你正在背叛联盟的命令
Your undertaking betrayed that code.
你告诉雷霄古我还活着?
You told Ra's I'm still alive?
他很高兴听到你没死
He was so grateful to hear it.
他特别希望亲手杀了你
Because he so very much wants to kill you himself.
Malcolm 我建议你...
So my advice to you, Malcolm...
跑路吧
Run.
Moira 咱们没完
This isn't finished, Moira.
你是谁?
Who are you?
跑龙套的
Merely a follower.
- 谁的手下?!  - 我兄弟
- Of who?!  - My brother.
他给你吃特效药了?
Did he give you the mirakuru?
他给你打了那种药吗?!
Did he inject you with it?!
没有 他用那药救了我
No. He saved me with it.
不
No.
醒醒
Please.
醒醒!
Please!
醒醒
Please.
- Oliver啊!  - Oliver啊!
- Oliver!  - Oliver!
他还活着吗?
Is he alive?
他脉搏很弱 但还有气 Oliver啊!
His pulse is weak, but it's there. Oliver!
听得见我说话吗?
Can you hear me?
他瞳孔张开了!
His pupils are dilated!
这是什么?
What the hell was that?
我不知道 加密了
I don't know, it's coded.
该死 该死!
Damn it. Damn it!
我进不了医疗站的程序
I can't break into the dispensary files.
我不知道他被打了什么药!
I have no idea what he was injected with!
什么毒
Poisoned with.
- 好吧 我们别无选择了  - 你干嘛?
- All right, we have no choice.  - What are you doing?
快叫救护车
Calling 9...1...1.
- Dig 等等!  - 不能再等了!
- Dig, wait!  - Can't wait!
我们怎么解释这一切?
How are we supposed to explain this?
所有人都会发现Oliver是绿箭侠!
Everyone's going to find out Oliver's the vigilante!
如果他死了就什么都没意义了
Which won't matter if he's dead.
Felicity 我们救不了他!
Felicity, we can't save him!
我懂 你说的对...
I know, you're right...
我们不能
We can't.
去中心城的单程票
One way to central city.
车已经离开10分钟
It left ten minutes ago.
果然还是晚了
Of course it did.
下一班什么时候?
When is the next one?
明天早上
In the morning.
啊
Ahh.
哦
Ohh.
救救我的朋友
Please save my friend.
-=圣城家园SCG字幕组 http://hd.cnscg.com/=-
仅供翻译交流使用, 禁止用于商业用途
协调: Tracy
时间轴: Pisces夜
翻译: 初见 水果哥 yjk8654 伊娃 西皮
校对: 潇妹纸